Guide to the Katipunan Ng Mga Demokratikong Pilipino (KDP) [Union of Democratic Filipinos] Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Katipunan ng mga Demokratikong Pilipino (KDP) [Union of Democratic Filipinos] records
1966-1988
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5889
Katipunan Ng Mga Demokratikong Pilipino
21.54 cubic feet (24 boxes)
Records relating to the policital organization Katipunan Ng Mga Demokratikong Pilipino (KDP) [Union of Democratic Filipinos]
The Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) is an organization that emerged in the Filipino American Community in 1973. As an organization the KDP embraced the dual goal of establishing socialism in the US, as well as supporting the National Democratic Movement led by the Communist Party of the Philippines (CPP). A central part of the mission of the KDP was fighting the regime of Philippines dictator Ferdinand Marcos, who had established marshall law when he seized power and represssed leftists and trade unionists in the Phillippines. Two of the KDP's Seattle members, Gene Viernes and Silme Domingo, were assassinated for their attempts to counter the Marcos regime and reform the Cannery Workers Union is Seattle. Marcos was later found guilty of orchestrating the attacks and found criminally liable in a US court.
Records, publications, photographic slides, and research files collected by the KDP in its activities. The collection also contains some materials on the history of the organization and its members.
Open to all users.
Katipunan Ng Mga Demokratikong Pilipino$vArchives
Personal Papers/Corporate Records;; Civic Activism; Labor History; Labor Unions
- Katipunan ng mga Demokratikong Pilipino (KDP) [Union of Democratic Filipinos] records, 1966-1988; 5889-001; 21.54 cubic feet (24 boxes)
  Records, publications, photographic slides, and research files collected by the KDP in its activities. The collection also contains some materials on the history of the organization and its members.
  Open to all users.
  Abraham Ignacio, 2015
  - SERIES I: NEWSPAPER FILES, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 1/1-2/25)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: East Bay: Blue Cross, 1977 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: East Bay: Project Manong Community Services Organizations, circa 1977 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: East Bay: Student Organizing/Youth, 1976 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Hawaii: PACE, Honolulu-Chinatown, Housing Struggle, Waihole-Waikane, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Hawaii: Ethnic Studies, University of Hawaii, 1976 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Hawaii: Land "War", Community Rift, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Hawaii: Labor Organizations, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Hawaii: Waihole-Waikane, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: New York: Aimee's Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) Harassment, 1979 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Pennsylvania: Pilipinos in Philadelphia, 1976 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: New York: Maids Sue United Nations (UN) Officials, 1976 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: New York: Foreign Medical Graduates (FMG) Campaign, National, Local, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: New York: Filipino Priest Harassed by Police, 1975 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: New York: Marc Schnapp, Father James Sinott Case, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Washington, D.C.: Community Organizations and Issues, Lechoco case, Wake Island, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Philadelphia: Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) to Deport Filipino Charged with Fraud, 1978 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Indiana: Filipina Faces Discrimination in Employment, 1976 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Ohio: Filipinos in Ohio Honor Jose Rizal, 1976 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Michigan: Pastors Want End to U.S. Aid to Philippines, 1976 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Walla Walla Prison Issue, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Police Spying, 1978 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Police Harassment of Filipino Community Activist, Angel Doniego, 1977 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: International Longshore and Warehouse Union (ILWU), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Paul Revere Apartments, 1979 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Filipino American Studies, 1977 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Teacher's Strike, Desegregation, 1978 (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Abuel-Almirante Case, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Providence Hospital, 1975 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: International District, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Alaska Cannery Workers Association (ACWA), 1973-1978 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Filipino Community of Seattle, Inc. (FCSI), 1979 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: United Pilipinos for Equal Employment (UPEE), Sandigan, Youth, Educational Center, Filipino American Council, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: West Coast Confederation of Pilipino Students, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Domatay Case, 1977 (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: San Francisco City College Youth Attacked by Campus Police, 1978 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Bareng Case, 1978 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Filipino Far West Task Force on Education, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: San Francisco Department of Social Services Guiltyi of Discrimination, 1977 (Box-folder 1/38)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Leticia Monserate Immigration Case, circa 1977 (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Asian Involvement Group (San Quentin Prison), 1976 (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: University of California Medical School Discrimination Case, circa 1977 (Box-folder 1/41)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Two Filipino U.S. Citizens Harassed by Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) Due to "Fake" Passports, 1978 (Box-folder 1/42)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Philippine Airlines Worker's Strike, 1979 (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Paul De Guzman, 1977 (Box-folder 1/44)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Proposition U, 1977 (Box-folder 1/45)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Right Wing Attack Against Katipunan ng mga Demokratikong Pilipino (KDP) Union of Democratic Filipinos, 1979 (Box-folder 1/46)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Adhoc Asian Caucus to Overturn Bakke Decision, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1/47)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: Foreign Medical Graduate Campaign, Filipino Alliance of Health Professionals, 1977 (Box-folder 1/48)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: San Francisco General Hospital Workers Stage Protest, 1978 (Box-folder 1/49)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Francisco: 4-H Trainee Issue, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/50)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Sacramento: Pilipino Bayanihan, Inc. Scandal, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/51)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Sacramento: California State Department of Health on Certification of Nurse's Aides, 1978 (Box-folder 1/52)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Sacramento: Dr. Antonio Saqueton Case-Health Care (Stockton), 1976 (Box-folder 1/53)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Los Angeles: Los Angeles Police Spying, 1978 (Box-folder 1/54)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Los Angeles: Pacheco Case - Bilingual Program, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/55)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Los Angeles: Pagkakaisa Center, Youth Organizing, Senior Citizens, 1976 (Box-folder 1/56)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Los Angeles: Filipino American Community of Los Angeles (FACLA), 1977-1979 (Box-folder 1/57)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Los Angeles: California State University at Long Beach, Ethnic Studies; Filipino American Studies, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1/58)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Los Angeles: Medicaid Fraud and Emmanuel David, 1977 (Box-folder 1/59)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Los Angeles: United Filipino American Assembly of Southern California (UFAASC), 1976 (Box-folder 1/60)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Los Angeles: United Farm Workers (UFW), 1977 (Box-folder 1/61)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Diego: Filipinos Join Protest Rally Against Klu Klux Klan, circa 1977 (Box-folder 1/62)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Diego: Filipino People's Far West Convention, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 1/63)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: San Diego: Hiring of Minorities, 1977 (Box-folder 1/64)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Union of Pan Asian Communities of San Diego (UPAC-SD), 1977 (Box-folder 1/65)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: West Coast Confederation of Filipino Students (WCCFS), 1976 (Box-folder 1/66)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Filipino World War 2 Veterans, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/67)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Punzalan Case, 1976 (Box-folder 1/68)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Prisons and prisoners, 1975 (Box-folder 1/69)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Police Brutality-Maxwell Case, 1972 (Box-folder 1/70)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Overseas Filipino Workers, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 1/71)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Agbayani Village, United Farmer Workers (UFW), 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/72)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Filipino Maids, 1976 (Box-folder 1/73)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Balikbayan Letters, 1976 (Box-folder 1/74)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Raoul Beloso Dies, 1975 (Box-folder 1/75)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Filipino Newspapers, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 1/76)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Filipino Labor Racket; Filipino Foreign Workers, 1975 (Box-folder 1/77)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: U.S. Opposition to Marcos Regime, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1/78)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Political Refugees, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/79)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: General Community Issues, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1/80)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: United States-Republic of the Philippines Relations Opinions, 1975 (Box-folder 1/81)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Community Organizations, 1975 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Filipino Seamen, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Hospital Workers, circa 1975 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Cannery Workers, 1978 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Mario Hermoso; Anti-Martial Law Protests, circa 1975 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: California Senate Bill 1 Demonstration, circa 1977 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Maguindanao Play/Skits/Cultural Endeavors Pictures, 1977 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Warbrides Skit Pictures, circa 1977 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: East Bay: Anti-Martial Law Activities, Movement for Free Philippine (MFP) Alliance, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Filipino Farm Workers Pictures, circa 1975 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Anti-Del Monte (Agribusiness) Demonstrations, Events, Etc., 1978 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: National Alliance for Fair Licensure of Foreign Nurse Graduates (NAFL-FNG), circa 1977 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: Filipino Community Political Activities, Assorted, circa 1979 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Silicon Valley Labor Organizing, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: United States-Republic of the Philippines Extradition Treaty, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Anti-Martial Law Coalition (AMLC) Philippines, circa 1977 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Consulate Sit-in, Anti-Martial Law Coalition 7, 1978 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper Files: Bakke Decision Photographs, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Gene Viernes/Silme Domingo Murder Newsclippings/Photographs, 1981 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Murder of Silme Domingo-Gene Viernes Newsclippings, 1981 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Seattle: International District Photographs, 1978 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Congress Education Project, 1978 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: June 12, Philippine Independence Day Celebration: Photographs, Leaflets, Program, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Filipino Community of Los Angeles (FACLA) Photographs, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper File: Filipino Peoples Far West Convention Photographs, Various, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 2/25)
  - SERIES II: WRITINGS AND FUND PROPOSALS, 1973-1989 (Box-folder 2/26-10/23)
    - Play: Isuda Ti Immuna (They Who Came First) script, 1976- (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Scripts for various Philippine-theme skits, circa 1973 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Ti Mangyuna (They Who Led the Way) Play Script, 1981 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - "Claring, A Warbride" Play Script, 1979 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Ti Mangyuna Funding Proposal, 1981 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Particularities of the role of music and particularities of song: music with lyrics, circa 1979 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Frame-Up of Narcisco-Perez Skit Script, 1978 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - Tagatupad (Those Who Must Carry On) Play Script, 1976 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Early funding proposals for Sining Bayan Theater Company, Foundation Proposals, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Zellerbach Family Fund proposals, 1978-1989 (Box-folder 2/35)
    - Limantour Fund proposals, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 2/36)
    - Isuda Ti Immuna (They Who Came First) Play Script, 1979 (Box-folder 2/37)
    - Master's Thesis: Mindanao, The Moro People's Resistance in the Philippines including "Mindanao" play script. 2 copies, 1978 (Box-folder 2/38)
    - "People of the Philippines v. Ferdinand Marcos" Play Script, circa 1978 (Box-folder 2/39)
    - "Maguindanao" Play Script, circa 1978 (Box-folder 2/40)
    - Mindanao Play Script, 1978 (Box-folder 2/41)
    - Various Philippine Left Newsletters, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Kalayaan International Newspaper: Philippine Community International News Service. (San Francisco, California), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - KDP People's Calendar, 1980 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - KDP People's Calendar, 1981 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Filipino American History Calendar: Project of Filipinos for Affirmative Action, 1989 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper (The Union), National Newspaper of the Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) (Oakland, California), 1973-1978 (Box-folder 4)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper (The Union), National Newspaper of the Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) (Oakland, California), 1979-1980 (Box-folder 5)
    - Ang Katipunan Newspaper (The Union), National Newspaper of the Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) (Oakland, California), 1981-1984 (Box-folder 6)
    - Katipunan Newspaper (The Union) Monthly Newsmagazine of the Filipino Community.(Independent, no longer associated with the Union of Democratic Filipinos.) (Oakland, California), 1984-1987 (Box-folder 7)
    - Katipunan Newspaper (The Union) Monthly Newsmagazine of the Filipino Community.(Independent, no longer associated with the Union of Democratic Filipinos.) (Oakland, California), 1987-1988 (Box-folder 8)
    - Katipunan Newspaper (The Union) Monthly Newsmagazine of the Filipino Community.(Independent, no longer associated with the Union of Democratic Filipinos.) (Oakland, California), 1988-1991 (Box-folder 9)
    - National Propaganda Commission: "Isuda Ti Immuna" Play Script/Program; "Mindanao" Play Souvenir Program, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Sining Bayan, Filipino American Performing Arts Company Dissolution, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Mindanao Play Souvenir Programs, Leaflets, Posters, 1978 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Maguindanao Play Scripts, Souvenir Programs, 1977 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - National Cultural Group (NCG): "Visions of a Warbride" KDP internal documents regarding play and tour, 1979 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) 10th Anniversay Slide Show Script, 1983 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - New People's Army (NPA) Acto Script, "Ang Bagong Hukbong Bayan" The New People's Army", 1976 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - "Sakada" Play Script and Souvenir Program, 1978 (Box-folder 10/8)
    - "Ti Mangyuna" (They Who Led the Way" Play Script, 1981 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - M.A. thesis: The Filipina Warbrides and the Second Wave Filipino Community in America, Research and the Dramatic Play with Music: "Claring, A Fil-Am Warbride", 1978 (Box-folder 10/10)
    - Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) 25th Anniversary Program, Slideshow script, 1998 (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Filipino National Day, Pista Sa Nayon 1977, Los Angeles, June 11-12 Souvenir Program, Media Packet/Training (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) Sham Independence Forum, Philippine National Day, 1978 (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Philippine National Day 1979, Los Angeles (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Philippine National Day 1980, San Diego (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Philippine National Day 1981, San Francisco (Box-folder 10/16)
    - University of California, Los Angeles: Samahang Pilipino, 1977 (Box-folder 10/17)
    - West Coast Confederation of Pilipino Students (WCCPS), 1976-1977 (Box-folder 10/18)
    - Pilipino People's Far West Convention, 1974 (Box-folder 10/19)
    - Pilipino People's Far West Convention, 1975 (Box-folder 10/20)
    - Pilipino People's Far West Convention, 1978 (Box-folder 10/21)
    - Filipino American Community Events: Los Angeles, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 10/22)
    - Pilipino People's Far West Convention, 1979 (Box-folder 10/23)
  - SERIES III: FILIPINO COMMUNITY LOS ANGELES, circa 1971-1987 (Box-folder 10/24-24)
    - United Filipino American Assembly: Los Angeles, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 10/24)
    - Filipino American Community of Los Angeles (FACLA) Report, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 10/25)
    - Committee to Reform Filipino American Community of Los Angeles (FACLA), 1977-1979 (Box-folder 10/26)
    - Fiipino American Community of Los Angeles (FACLA) Correspondence, 1977 (Box-folder 10/27)
    - Filipino American Community of Los Angeles (FACLA) Legal Case, Newsletters, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 10/28)
    - Alona Case, 1979 (Box-folder 10/29)
    - National Alliance for Fair Licensure of Foreign Nurse Graduates, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 10/30)
    - Narciso-Perez Case, 1977 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - California Senate Bill 1870: Filipino Categorization, 1977 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - National Task Force for the Defense of Immigrant Rights (NFIRO), 1980 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Friends of the Filipino People (FFP), 1973-1979 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Alliance Against Martial Law (AAML-Philippines), 1976-1977 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Anti-Martial Law Alliance (AMLA-Philippines) San Diego, 1979 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Anti-Martial Law Coalition (AMLC) Philippines, National Conference, 1978 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Anti-Martial Law Coalition (AMLC) Philippines, National Conference, 1979 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Anti-Martial Law Coalition (AMLC) Philippiines, National Conference, 1980 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Extradition of Anti-Martial Law Activists, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Salvaging (Summary executions) in the Philippines, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Marcos Visit to the United States, 1980 (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Anti-Martial Law Alliance (AMLA) Christmas Caroling Campaigns, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 11/13)
    - September 22 (Anniversary of the declaration of Martial Law in the Philippines) Campaign, 1980 (Box-folder 11/14)
    - "Marcos Lifts Martial Law" Campaign, 1981 (Box-folder 11/15)
    - "The Muslim People and the Struggle in Mindanao" Forum, 1978 (Box-folder 11/16)
    - September 22 (Anniversary of the declaration of martial law in the Philippines) Speech, 1978 (Box-folder 11/17)
    - New People's Army Tableau Script and Guidelines, 1978 (Box-folder 11/18)
    - National Steering Committee (NSC), Committee to Advance the Movement for Democracy and Independence (CAMDI) Philippines, 1987 (Box-folder 11/19)
    - Various Anti-Martial Law Movement Pamphlets, Newsletters, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 11/20)
    - Kalayaan (Freedom): A cultural presentation, Filipino Study Group of Montreal (FSG), 1978 (Box-folder 11/21)
    - Renato Constantino pamphlets, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11/22)
    - Mindanao Play script (partial), 1978 (Box-folder 11/23)
    - Visions of a Warbride script, 1979 (Box-folder 11/24)
    - Resource Center for Philippine Concerns (RCPC), circa 1982 (Box-folder 11/25)
    - "Trick or Treat" Script (How to extradite political offenders the Marcos' Way), 1980 (Box-folder 11/26)
    - Gene Viernes: Poetry (drafts), circa 1979 (Box-folder 11/27)
    - Makibaka! Revolutionary poems and songs from the Philippines, 1974 (Box-folder 11/28)
    - "People of the Philippines v. Ferdinand Marcos" play script, circa 1978 (Box-folder 11/29)
    - Nilo Tayag, "On Commitment" essay, circa 1970 (Box-folder 11/30)
    - "Serve the People through Art and Culture" handout, circa 1973 (Box-folder 11/31)
    - File 12: Anti-Martial Law Coalition (AMLC) Philippines Caroling Campaign Guidelines, 1980 (Box-folder 11/32)
    - "Mr. Marcos goes to Washington or Reagan's foreign policy: Marcos finds a friend" slideshow script, 1980 (Box-folder 11/33)
    - Slideshow scripts: Immigration, Racism, circa 1980 (Box-folder 11/34)
    - Filipino National Day: Chicago, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 11/35)
    - Essay: Philippine Literature: The Realist Position, circa 1975 (Box-folder 11/36)
    - Essay: Asian Theatre of Communion: A Look at Contemporary Philippine Theatre, Doreen Fernandez, circa 1980 (Box-folder 11/37)
    - Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) Chapter File: Hawaii, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 11/38)
    - Manuscript: Life of Bonipasy in Hawaii, circa 1970 (Box-folder 11/39)
    - Filipino prisoner, Lucio Viacrucis, letter to Ang Katipunan, 1976 (Box-folder 11/40)
    - Essay: Filipinos in Hawaii: The First 75 Years. Dean Alegado, Cathi Tactaquin, 1980 (Box-folder 11/41)
    - Roadblocks to Community Building: A Case Study of the Stockton Filipino Community Center Projects, 1970 (Box-folder 11/42)
    - Land Use Change in Hawaii. Hawaii Communities Unite, Organize and Fight Back. Ethnic Studies Class 221. University of Hawaii at Manoa., 1975 (Box-folder 11/43)
    - Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) "Warbrides" Campaign guidelines and slide show script, 1979 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Union of Democratic Filipinos (KDP) Various political slide show scripts (1), circa 1976 (Box-folder 12/2)